本视频由大疆赞助
Sponsored by DJI.
好吧 我觉得我可以这么说
All right, I think I'm allowed to say this
所以我做视频已经超过15年了
so I've been making videos for like 15 plus years now
但在YouTube上 有些事情实际上让人意外
and there's something actually kind of counterintuitive
在YouTube上
that happens on YouTube
人们反而更喜欢低制作价值的视频
where people are more drawn to Almost like lower production value videos
比如那些大灯光的内容
like obviously big lights
当然 摄像机等设备都很有趣
and cameras and everything are super fun
不过 人们更想看到真实的生活
and but people just want to see real life
就是用你手边的任何相机拍摄的现实场景
like what's happening in front of you
with whatever camera you have with you.
所以 尽管我对视频制作非常痴迷
So while I'm a huge video nerd
我已经换过几台相机
and I've graduated a few times from,
从我的第一台普通相机到第一台单反相机
you know, my first camera to my first DSLR
再到一台电影摄影机
to a cinema camera
而这些相机其实用起来变得越来越复杂
and these cameras actually get like harder and harder to use
但我真的想回归到随意拍摄 去更多的地方
but I actually want to get back more into shooting just like more places,
更多自发地去获取经历和探索不同的地方
just more spontaneously and more experiences and more locations
而不仅仅是我们擅长的那种面对镜头的说话类型
not just the talking head stuff that we've gotten really good at.
这确实还是挺有趣的 不过
It's still fun, but like
我们想要更多地出去走走 你懂吗？
we want to just get out more, you know?
总之 那些设备的最佳选择是
So anyway, the sort of apex for that gear is
你可能会以为我说的是智能手机
you might have thought I was going to say smartphones
其实我说的是像这样的运动相机
but it's like an action camera like this
而且它甚至更小了
like it's even smaller.
它随时都能陪着你
It can go everywhere with you.
它更加坚固耐用
It's more rugged.
它随时都能拍摄到所有内容
It can shoot everything all the time.
这让我思考
And that got me thinking, well
我接触这些运动相机已经快10年了
it's been almost 10 years since I got into these action cameras
那么 现在最好的运动相机有多厉害呢？
and How good are the best ones now?
你可能还记得那天我们把相机绑在Mac身上的场景
Like you might remember when we strapped one onto Mac that one day
那时我用4K摄像机记录了狗的视角 时间是2014年
and got the perspective of being a dog in 4K. That was 2014.
所以和那个类似
So similar to that
这次也不是评测
this one also isn't a review
这次是大疆赞助的 他们送来了这个
but this one is sponsored by DJI and they've got this,
这是他们最新的高端运动相机 Action 5 Pro
their newest, latest and greatest, highest end action camera into my hands.
所以这就是大疆的Action 5 Pro
So this is the Action 5 Pro.
我打算用它深入探索希望能带来更多可能的技术
And I figured I'd use this to take a deeper look at the tech
希望能
that's gonna hopefully
让我能进行更多自由风格的拍摄
enable more of this more freestyle shooting that I do.
预计在2025年
in 2025.
运动相机明显的第一个优点就是
So the first obvious advantage of the action camera
它非常耐用
is just how tough it's built
because yes
智能手机录制视频表现出色
we know smartphones can do an incredible job with video too
但我想你一定会有不同的看法
but I don't know about you.
我可不想在这种危险情况下拿我的手机冒险
I'm just not trying to risk my phone and all these precarious scenarios
或者找到一个好角度拍摄会很不错
or it would be cool to get an angle
你只需把相机放在某个地方就可以了
or you put the camera someplace
那里可能会掉下或被撞到
where it could fall or get smacked around
要是我的手机碰了一下可就麻烦了
or take a beating because that's my phone.
这一点从一开始就是不争的事实
So this has always been true since the beginning.
这台设备完全防水
I mean, this thing is airtight.
它的外形就像坦克一样坚固
It's built like a tank.
无需保护套 防水深度达20米
It's waterproof to 20 meters with no case needed.
比很多智能手机更出色
much better than most smartphones.
而且它的耐温性也很强
And then it's also super temperature resistant.
工作温度范围为零下20℃到45℃
So it can operate anywhere from negative 20 Celsius to 45 Celsius.
我会在屏幕上显示华氏温度
I'll also put the Fahrenheit on the screen for y'all
在这些温度下不会有结冰或过热的问题
but no freezing or overheating in any of these temperatures
这可真是太疯狂了
which is kind of nuts.
所以更耐用、更小巧的特点
So being more durable and smaller than any smartphone
在很多情况下是明显的优势
is a pretty obvious advantage
在多种场景中 这对运动相机来说是个明显的优点
to the action camera in a lot of situations.
不过这些设备在使用上经过多年的改进
But the other thing about these things is they've gotten a lot
在可用性上的提升
of usability upgrades
变得更加实用了
over the years.
我记得以前的日子
So I remember back in the day
以前这些相机只有单一的后屏幕
these used to just be back screens
有点像是要瞄准的感觉
which is kind of like point
然后就拍摄 希望一切顺利
and shoot and cross your fingers if you're on the other side.
不过现在 它们都有了双屏设计
But now, now they've all got these dual screens.
前后都有屏幕
So you've got a screen on the front and on the back
这在任意方向构图时非常方便
which is really convenient for framing things up in either direction.
而且这个型号还配备了高亮度的OLED屏幕
And this one also happens to have these high brightness OLED screens.
所以即使在户外或者很亮的环境下
So even if it's outside or something super bright
我可以同时使用两个屏幕
I can use both screens.
而且这是一个触控屏 非常好用
And since it's a touchscreen and it's actually usable
我可以方便地切换设置
I can flip through settings
并调整设置 确保我的构图合适
and adjust things and get my framing right.
无论是哪一侧
on either side.
其实这非常实用
It's actually very useful.
所以这在其他方面也有了提升
So this actually levels up in one other way.
它有个我觉得应该更普遍的功能
It has a feature that I think should be more common than it is
就是内置存储空间
which is internal storage.
这款相机内置了47个GB的存储空间
So this camera has 47 gigs of internal storage.
等一下 祖里
Hold on, Zuri.
这就意味着我已经因此省了好几次心
Which means it saved me a couple times already
因为我忘了去拿内存卡
where I forget to go get a memory card
但我内置的存储足够用来录制视频
but I still have enough storage built in to record.
我希望所有相机都有这个功能
Petition for all cameras to have that.
我觉得它们应该都这样
I think they should all do it.
它们应该都有内置录制功能 这样就能随时录制
They should all have internal recording so they can just record whenever.
如果我有卡的话
And if I have a card
那么我可以录得更多
then I can record more.
这样就足够了……
So this will do...
这是47个G的容量
This is 47 gigs.
时长为两个小时
It's two hours.
我可以用一段时间了
I'm good for a while.
好吧 去自在地探索吧
Alright, run free.
去好好探索吧
Go explore.
电池续航表现非常出色
Battery life is very solid.
如果把屏幕关掉 连续录制四个小时
Up to four hours non-stop recording if you turn the screen off.
而大疆的无人机也配有类似的智能充电器
And then DJI has a similar clever charger that they have with their drones.
也就是说 把所有电池放进这个充电盒
Basically where if you put all of the batteries in this case
然后为盒子充电
and then charge the case
它会逐一给它们充电
it just hops each of them up.
相机会快速充电
And the camera itself actually will quick charge
只需直接连接即可
if you just plug it right in
USB-C
with the USB-C.
我不知道功率是多少 但是……
I don't have a wattage, but...
我插电开始时电量为0% 四分钟充到了20%
I plugged it in at zero and it got to 20% in four minutes
然后40分钟后充满电
and then it was full in 40.
此外 还配有压力传感器
There's also a pressure sensor
可以随时显示你在水下的深度
so you can tell at any time how deep underwater you are
或者你当前的海拔高度
or how high of an altitude you're at
如果你对此拍摄感兴趣的话
if that's what you're interested in shooting.
而且还有很多配件
And also then there's just a bunch of accessories for it
可以帮助你拍摄各种角度
for building out and shooting whatever angle
你想拍摄什么都可以
whatever subject you want.
所以可能像这样的奇怪东西吧
So maybe something kind of weird like this.
等我一下下
Give me a second.
我通常不太敢把手机放在
I would normally not at all be comfortable putting my phone out
面前
in front of me
像这样挥杆打高尔夫
hitting golf balls like this,
不过这个角度还蛮酷的
but kind of cool angle.
这款相机最棒的特点是
Probably one of the best things about this camera is it attaches
可以连接各种配件
to any accessory
you want
通过底部的磁性快拆系统 很方便
by this magnetic quick release system at the bottom
在过去的几年里 这款设备已经相对标准化了
which has been pretty standardized with this thing for the past few years.
我觉得其他公司也开始陆续跟进了
I think other companies are starting to follow along too.
说实话 这款的好处在于
Matter of fact, the benefits of this one specifically
因为它是大疆出品
since it's made by DJI
它可以直接与大疆其他产品兼容
it's directly compatible with other things DJI also makes,
例如他们最新的麦克风 Mic 2
like their newest mics, the Mic 2.
所以你可以很方便地直接将它与运动相机配对
So you can pair that easily straight to the action cam
而且可以从内置麦克风获取音频
and get scratch audio from the built-in microphones.
除此之外
On top of all of that
它实际上可以即插即用 作为网络摄像头
it actually plug and plays as a webcam.
所以 当你插上的时候
So when you plug it in
在选项中选择网络摄像头
the options come up, select webcam,
这确实提升了很多人的使用体验
and actually levels up a lot of people's webcam experiences
这真是太棒了
which is pretty sick.
使用前记得把它擦干净
Just remember to brush the dust off of it before you actually do.
但画质一定要好
But it's got to look good.
其实这一切的意义在于
Like the whole point of this is
你可以随时携带这台相机
that you have this camera everywhere with you
但拍摄的画面得好看
but that the footage actually looks good.
如果画面不好 前面说的一切都没意义
So none of this matters if the footage doesn't look good.
所以这款2024年的运动相机算得上是最好的
So this action cam in 2024 has one of the best.
它配备了1/1.3英寸的传感器 支持120帧每秒的4K录制
It has a 1 over 1.3 inch sensor that can shoot up to 4K at 120 FPS
如果想的话 可以用慢动作拍摄
slow-mo if you want to.
现在有几款高端智能手机
There are a couple other high-end smartphones out right now
传感器差不多大小
with roughly the same size sensor.
我觉得1/1.3英寸的传感器和Galaxy S23 Ultra是相同的
I actually think 1 over 1.3 inches is the same as the Galaxy S23 Ultra
所以这是个很好的例子
so that's a good example.
所以 F2.8镜头足够大 可以收集很多光线
So big enough to gather plenty of light is an F2.8 lens.
而且
And on top of that
因为它是一款专用相机
since it's a dedicated camera, yes
它支持拍摄log格式
it can shoot log.
它配备了10位D-Log M格式
It's got a 10-bit D-Log M.
它具备HLG功能
It's got HLG so
你可以获得更多的动态范围
that you can get even more dynamic range
这让你在后期编辑时有更多选择
to mess with in editing after the fact.
当然你也可以选择普通拍摄模式
Of course, you can always just shoot normal mode if you want
不过如果你需要更大的动态范围
but if you ever want that extra range
在触摸屏上轻松一滑就能切换
it's just a quick flip away on the touchscreen settings.
它的视角非常广阔
And it has one of the widest fields of view.
运动相机的特点是视角极广
This is the thing about action cameras is they get super wide
不过这款相机拥有155度的视角
but this one is 155 degrees.
这给你提供了广阔的拍摄空间
So it gives you a ton of room to work with
如果你想拍摄超广角模式的话
if you want to shoot in the most ultra-wide mode
但是裁剪模式的失真更少了
but there's also less distortion in the more cropped modes
这要看你拍摄的内容
depending on what you're shooting.
其实拍摄像驾驶这样的一人称视角完全足够宽
It's actually plenty wide enough to shoot first-person stuff like driving,
比如在正常模式下或驾驶时
for example, in normal mode, or driving.
比如说
for example.
无需失真效果
No distortion needed.
接下来 我要谈的最后一点是
So that brings me to my last point
也就是物超所值
which is just bang for the buck.
像这样的小相机 可以随身带着
Like a tiny camera like this that you can take everywhere
比你冒险用的智能手机便宜多了
is going to be cheaper than a smartphone that you put at risk
你花在手机上的时间
all the time that you actually use for your phone.
这款相机起售价349块钱
So this camera, starts at 349 bucks.
而且不要忘了它的内置存储
And also let's not forget the internal storage that it comes with.
你可以挑一款来试试
So you can pick one of these up
还有各种配件和支架
and however many accessories and mounts
随便带上你需要的东西 出去玩
and things you want and run around outside
你可以随意使用 让它冒风险
and beat it up and put it at risk all the time.
到最后
And then at the end of the day
如果它还好好的
if it's still fine
把它带回来 想用的时候可以做网摄
bring it back and use it as a webcam if you want.
从这些小相机带来的乐趣中 我的主要收获是
So I think the main thing that I've taken away from all the fun
that I've had with these little cameras is, you know
有句名言说
there's that famous quote
谁说的我也忘了
I don't know who said it
最好的相机 就是随身携带的那台
but the best camera is the one you have with you.
这句话到处可闻
You always hear that quoted everywhere.
我也越来越认同这句话
And I think I've been leaning into that more
因为我经常没有带着相机
because of how often I don't have my camera with me,
比如那种电影相机
like the cinema camera,
那台超级高端的红色相机
the super high end, the red camera.
我能想起很多这样的例子 例如
There are a ton of instances that I can recall of like, say
我正在进行一项科技评测
I'm doing a tech review
设备上发生了一些很酷的事情
and there's something really cool that happens on a device
或者是一种用手机拍摄的场景
or maybe like a shooting scenario with a smartphone camera.
我可以事后跟你说发生了什么
And I can kind of just tell you after the fact about what happened
而不是用相机指着它给你看
instead of actually having the camera to point at it and show you.
我想更经常带着相机
I want to just have the camera with me more often
这样我就能把东西展示给你
and just be able to show you the thing.
但我并不是说
So what I'm definitely not saying is
我可没打算放弃那些高端相机
that I'm like done with, you know, the super high end fun cameras.
我还是很喜欢它们
I still love them.
我们为什么总是用红色相机在摄影棚拍摄 是有原因的
There's a reason why we shoot so much stuff with the Reds and in the studio
而这种拍摄方式始终有其价值
and that will always have its place.
但我今后特别希望能更频繁地随身带相机
But what my goal is going forward especially is to have the camera
with me more often.
当然 我口袋里会放着手机
Obviously I'll have my smartphone in my pocket
而我希望随身始终带着相机
but just having a camera all the time everywhere whether it's in my pocket
不论是在包里还是其他地方
or in my bag or whatever so
这样一旦有拍摄机会 我就能抓住它
that when that shooting scenario comes up I can capture it
而这些画面可以放进视频里
and that can actually go in the video.
这正是我想做的
That's what I'm trying to do.
希望你能理解我说的这些
Hopefully you're with me on that
也希望你能期待这些视频的上线
and hopefully you're down to see those videos when they come out.
你想看那段视频的话
Also if you want to see that video
很快会在自动对焦频道上线
that'll be on the Autofocus channel pretty soon.
非常疯狂的视频哦
Pretty crazy one.
那么 欢迎在评论区告诉我你的想法哦
Anyway, let me know what you think in the comments.
谢谢你们的观看！
Thanks for watching.
下次再见啦！
I'll catch you in the next one.
保持快乐！
Peace.